<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tools | Tech Opener]]></title>
  <link href="http://techopener.com/blog/categories/tools/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://techopener.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-03T12:34:44-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://techopener.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kenan Shifflett]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Full Text Search with Dropbox]]></title>
    <link href="http://techopener.com/blog/2011/04/full-text-search-with-dropbox/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-25T18:58:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://techopener.com/blog/2011/04/full-text-search-with-dropbox</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://db.tt/BKfYgZE">Dropbox</a> + <a href="http://lucene.apache.org/solr/">Solr</a> =
full text indexing and search for files in your Dropbox. I wrote an app in
<a href="http://www.sinatrarb.com/">Sinatra</a> that authenticates to Dropbox, downloads
your files, and indexes them in Solr. It also provides a simple interface for
searching that includes hit highlighting and some basic facet support.</p>

<p><a href="/images/searchdropbox.png"><img src="/images/searchdropbox.png" alt="Search Dropbox" /></a></p>

<p>I've posted the project on <a href="https://github.com/nanek/searchdropbox">github</a>,
so feel free to download and try it. For anyone interested in this as a hosted
service instead of as a download and install, let me know.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analyzing data from DonorsChoose.org]]></title>
    <link href="http://techopener.com/blog/2011/04/analyzing-data-from-donorschoose-org/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-14T12:28:38-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://techopener.com/blog/2011/04/analyzing-data-from-donorschoose-org</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>DonorsChoose.org is running a <a href="http://www.donorschoose.org/hacking-%0Aeducation">contest</a> by opening up its data for analysis and use in innovative
applications.  They have provided data dumps for project, search, donation and
gift card data in large csv files.  There are a two free tools that I
recommend to quickly review this data.</p>

<p><a href="http://code.google.com/p/google-refine/">Google Refine</a> allows you to filter
the data and identify data quality issues.  It also makes it very easy to
manipulate and transform the data any way you like.  Bulk replacements and
column transforms are two of its strengths.  Another cool feature is the
ability to template exports into different formats such as JSON.  Heres some
tips I found with working with the Donors Choose data.  First increase the
<a href="http://code.google.com/p/google-%0Arefine/wiki/FaqAllocateMoreMemory">memory settings</a>.  Second, update the <a href="http://code.google.com/p/google-refine/issues/detail?id=31#c6">facet limit
setting</a> to
something higher.  The <a href="http://code.google.com/p/google-refine/">screencasts</a>
for Google Refine do a great job in demonstrating its use.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.google.com/fusiontables/">Google Fusion Tables</a> is good for
visualizing data in various ways like charts, maps, or timelines.  This tool
works better with data sets that are already cleaned up.  It takes some time
to load the data and process it, so it is best served for working with just a
slice of data that you would like to present for a specific purpose.  It does
have a 250mb limit per user and a 100mb limit per csv file.</p>

<p>So go ahead and start analyzing this data.  It is for a good cause and the
lucky contest winner will get to meet Steven Colbert!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Online password security]]></title>
    <link href="http://techopener.com/blog/2011/03/online-password-security/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-03T16:22:42-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://techopener.com/blog/2011/03/online-password-security</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I often find myself forgetting my passwords and usernames to various sites.
So recently, I decided to get serious about password management.  I use
<a href="http://www.keepassx.org/">KeyPassX</a> (or KeyPass if you are using windows) as
a secure way to encrypt and record the urls, usernames and passwords to sites.</p>

<p>I also signed up for <a href="http://www.google.com/suppor%0At/accounts/bin/static.py?hl=en&amp;page=guide.cs&amp;guide=1056283&amp;topic=1056284">Google 2 step verification</a>.
This is useful for many reasons, but one in particular is that your gmail
account contains a lot of information that can be used to access your other
accounts.  Once you get past the initial setup, everything works seamlessly as
it did before.  Enterprises have traditionally paid big bucks to implement
this type of 2 factor authentication, typically requiring issuing RSA tokens
or similar to all employees.  It's great to see a more integrated solution
being provided directly to consumers.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.dropbox.com">Dropbox</a> has nothing to do with your password
security, however it is a great tool to sync files between your computer, web,
and devices.  So one way to always be sure that you don't lose your KeyPass
database or your Google verification backup codes is to place them in a
private dropbox folder that you can reach from everywhere.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Network Monitoring with Zenoss]]></title>
    <link href="http://techopener.com/blog/2009/09/network-monitoring-with-zenoss/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-10T08:00:16-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://techopener.com/blog/2009/09/network-monitoring-with-zenoss</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I configured <a href="http://www.zenoss.com/">Zenoss</a> for a client to allow
them to be more proactive and receive email notifications when a service or
server goes down on their network.  When you are frequently upgrading or
modifying applications there are bound to be issues that crop up and cause
failures.  It is best to be aware of these and correct them before your users
notice.</p>

<p>To get started you can download a Virtual appliance with Zenoss already
installed.  Once it is up and running, you will want to install a few ZenPacks
that are relevant to your environment.  These are basically just extensions to
the product that can give you more specific collection and reporting tools.
The next step is ensure there is an SNMP agent running on the machines you
plan to monitor.  SNMP is a common network monitoring protocol and an basic
agent comes with Windows.</p>

<p>Once you have the basic ZenPacks and SNMP running you can have Zenoss discover
all your servers and network devices, or you can add individual servers as
needed.</p>

<p>Zenoss will model each device, determine what software, services, ports, disk
drives are on the device and assign default thresholds and alerts to each.
For example if a disk drive is more than 90% of capacity it will create an
event message.  These messages will start displaying in nicely color-coded
dashboards for now.  The next logical step is to setup email notifications by
defining alert rules per user or group.  Alert rules allow you to filter the
event messages and only receive the ones that are important to you such as
only Production systems that throw Error messages.</p>

<p>If you are in need of a monitoring solution, I highly recommend you give
Zenoss a try.  It really is quite easy to setup and has a vibrant community
behind it with a lot more advanced capabilities than I have discussed here.
Also take a look at a ramp up video put together by JumpBox for Zenoss at
<a href="http://vimeo.com/6408567">http://vimeo.com/6408567</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remote Desktop Manager]]></title>
    <link href="http://techopener.com/blog/2009/08/remote-desktop-manager/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-10T20:56:16-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://techopener.com/blog/2009/08/remote-desktop-manager</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you find yourself managing a number of Windows servers take a look at
<a href="http://www.code4ward.net/main/RoyalTS/Download.aspx">Royal TS 1.5.1</a>.</p>

<p>Royal TS allows you to organize your connections to multiple servers over RDP.
There are other programs that do this, but this one allows you to easily
categorize, sort and search the list.  It saves all of your settings in a XML,
which you can easily share with other co-workers as they join the project.</p>

<p><a href="/images/RoyalTS.png"><img src="/images/RoyalTS_thumb.png" alt="RoyalTS" /></a></p>

<p>The latest version is shareware, however I use the freeware 1.5.1 version and
it works great!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
