<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mobile | Tech Opener]]></title>
  <link href="http://nanek.github.com/blog/categories/mobile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nanek.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-06T22:00:26-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://nanek.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kenan Shifflett]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Credit Cards and Security]]></title>
    <link href="http://nanek.github.com/blog/2011/07/credit-cards-and-security/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-07T08:04:54-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nanek.github.com/blog/2011/07/credit-cards-and-security</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently returned from a wonderful trip to Norway.  One tech thing that
stood out was that everywhere you go there they have portable card readers
that read cards with a chip or magnetic stripe.  Looking into it, the "chip"
is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EMV">EMV</a> technology adopted in Europe in
2005 due to security concerns.  Every single place I tried to use my non-chip
credit or debit card came with a puzzled look and the statement, "no chip?!"
Being a tech geek I definitely felt out of date.  You could tell by the way
they acted that they didn't swipe cards very often, as everyone only uses the
chip there.</p>

<p>I remember when I applied for my first credit card, the American Express Blue
card, which I still have.  It came with a USB card reader and a chip in the
card to help secure online transactions.  I never used the card reader, but it
was the main reason I got the card, and that was back in 1999.  Unfortunately
that is not an EMV chip, so it doesn't work in Europe.</p>

<p>Swipe cards, just like plain text account numbers lack any sort of security.
This is widely known, however we currently have a chicken/egg problem of not
many cards with chips and not many readers for these chips in the US.
<a href="https://squareup.com/">Square</a> and other companies are making card readers
more accessible, however is still based upon fundamentally insecure swipe card
technology. Some say mobile payments, such as
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Near_field_communication">NFC</a> will provide a
more secure technology and are more practical to deploy in the US over EMV
technology.</p>

<p>Frankly, I don't care too much what technology is used, however I would prefer
the option to choose a more secure credit/debit card.  Seems like there
shouldn't be an issue supporting both.  Recently I just go a new ING Direct
MasterCard, that has no embossed numbers on the card.  In fact, all of the
account information such as my name and account number and expiration are
printed on the back.  It certainly looks cool, albeit almost fake, and it
won't leave my CC number imprinted in my wallet, however im not sure it makes
it my account any more secure.  I guess they decided that no one makes card
imprints anymore.</p>

<p>Im looking forward to see some innovation in banking over the next year.
Seems like the market is poised for a shake-up.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Location history reporting]]></title>
    <link href="http://nanek.github.com/blog/2011/03/location-history-reporting/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-07T11:20:54-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://nanek.github.com/blog/2011/03/location-history-reporting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are lots of mobile location sharing products and many new ones everyday.
Most of them appear to be centered around location check-ins and sharing with
friends.  While this is neat, it seems like only a small slice of the use
cases in which location data is useful.</p>

<p>For example, lets say that I take I-66 W to work everyday, starting around
9am.  If this pattern is established, and there is an accident on I-66 W at
8:50am, it would be great to know that before I start my commute.  The
location and time of this event is important in that if it was another road or
at another time, then I really don't care to be informed regarding this event.
Unless the event was at 9:30am and im running late.  In order to provide
context aware alerts, you need to have sufficient data in order to have a good
level of confidence that a user is likely to take an action at a certain time
and place.</p>

<p>Certainly there are existing ways to be informed regarding traffic situations.
However, it seems to me that we have not taken automation regarding similar
use cases yet to a usable level.  Smart phones that are aways on, full of
sensors and generally always with us, empower us to easily track, record,
analyze and alert with minimal or no input.  I've started to explore how to
implement this and I hope to discuss it more over the next few days.</p>

<p>&amp;nbsp_place_holder;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smartphone with unlimited everything for $25/month]]></title>
    <link href="http://nanek.github.com/blog/2011/03/smartphone-with-unlimited-everything/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-02T10:37:12-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://nanek.github.com/blog/2011/03/smartphone-with-unlimited-everything</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Virgin Mobile offers a great $25/month plan for unlimited data, text and web
with 300 talk minutes with no contract to sign.  This works great for me, as I
generally just have short phone conversations.  However there are of course
times when I might get stuck on the phone for an hour or so.  Below are a few
extra steps I took to help get around the 300 minute limit without spending
any more.</p>

<p>First, I ported my number to <a href="http://voice.google.com">Google Voice</a>(GV).  GV
has a lot of features, but the key feature is being able to indicate where to
forward calls to when your phone number is dialed.  For example, when my GV
number is called, it is then forwarded to my mobile phone number.</p>

<p>Secondly, I setup GV to forward to Google Talk within Gmail.  Im often in
front of a computer, so this way I can easily make and receive phone calls for
free without using my cell minutes or using a different phone number.</p>

<p>Lastly, to take it the extra mile, what about a VOIP call when you are on your
cell phone in order to avoid using your minutes?  Might as well use that
unlimited data plan.  Turns out that there are a few extra steps here, however
it is relatively easy to setup.  I use a
<a href="http://www.google.com/gizmo5/">Gizmo5</a> SIP account for this and I won't go
into the details here, but there are
<a href="http://iiordanov.blogspot.com/2009/07/sipdroid-gv-guava.html">plenty</a> of
<a href="http://code.google.com/p/google-voice-sipsorcery-dialplans/w/list">posts</a> on
the web describing how to set this up.  Keep in mind though that the call
quality of this often does suffer based on the quality of the data connection.</p>

<p>If you sign up for a <a href="http://www.virginmobileusa.com/">Virgin Mobile</a> account,
feel free to use the Kickback Code IYFUMN7I for an extra 60 minutes of talk
time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPad apps]]></title>
    <link href="http://nanek.github.com/blog/2010/04/ipad-apps/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-02T08:35:36-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nanek.github.com/blog/2010/04/ipad-apps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Prepared for tomorrow by downloading some iPad applications before the device
has even been released.  Apple = Hype machine.  iPad will win for the same
reasons the iPhone did.  For anyone not paying attention, it is the
applications.</p>

<p><a href="/images/iPadApps.png"><img src="/images/iPadApps.png" alt="iPad Apps" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Foursquare on Windows Mobile]]></title>
    <link href="http://nanek.github.com/blog/2009/12/foursquare-on-windows-mobile/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-22T21:47:50-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://nanek.github.com/blog/2009/12/foursquare-on-windows-mobile</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://foursquare.com">Foursquare </a>does not have a windows mobile version of
their application, so I thought it would be a great opportunity to try and
build an app.</p>

<p>Things that are working fairly well:</p>

<ul>
<li>Foursquare API access.</li>
<li>JSON.NET is used to parse the JSON responses.</li>
<li>sqlite is used for caching http responses.</li>
<li>OAuth is used for authentication to foursquare.</li>
<li><p>GPS lookup.
Things that don't work and have proved difficult to implement:</p></li>
<li><p>Responsiveness.  At times the app stops responding and overall feels too slow for normal use.</p></li>
<li>Cell ID lookup.  This is important as GPS often does not work indoors.  It appears access to this API may be protected on most phones.</li>
<li><p>Good looking user interface.  Plus dealing with different phone resolutions, orientations, and sizes makes it a little more complicated.
Things that would be interesting to implement but require a solid base
application:</p></li>
<li><p>Map integration</p></li>
<li>Integration with other API's such as Yelp
You can find the source at
<a href="http://foursquare.codeplex.com">http://foursquare.codeplex.com</a> along with a
CAB for installation on your phone if you want to try it out.  Look under the
planned download section.  It works ok on my HTC Touch Pro.  If you are
interested in contributing to this effort, let me know.  I'm debating spending
more time on making this work better or building a HTML5 based mobile web
application.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
